<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://yifeijing.github.io</id>
    <title>Moriturus Te Saluto</title>
    <updated>2023-09-03T00:27:20.263Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://yifeijing.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://yifeijing.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Yifei&apos;s personal blog!</subtitle>
    <logo>https://yifeijing.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://yifeijing.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2023, Moriturus Te Saluto</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yokohama City Exploring]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/yokohama-city-exploring/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/yokohama-city-exploring/">
        </link>
        <updated>2023-08-06T13:16:24.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Went to Yokohama with Zeta on this weekend. This was the first time I actually explored Yokomaha. Only because of the ADs of a Izakaya called San-yo.<br>
This place is so treacherous that you even do not want to give a word to scrit.<br>
Firstly, it is impossible that Mao and Zhou or Yang Guifei have been there to taste just the dumplings and ramen. Secondly, even they did pay a visit there, I do not think they would be so surprised at the food. Thirdly, the name of the food on the menu is so brutal.<br>
<img src="https://yifeijing.github.io/post-images/1691753101736.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
<img src="https://yifeijing.github.io/post-images/1691753215444.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
Can you imagine the taste of virgin pigs, or the taste of &quot;chinchin&quot; in the ramen?<br>
They have these abnormal names to let you try them. You know it is just normal Chinese cuisine though, you would like to accept the challenge.<br>
<img src="https://yifeijing.github.io/post-images/1691753379116.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
What's more? There was even quotes of Mao, but they obviously fake. Yeah, so obvious that you know it is that a joke.</p>
<p>For the quality of food, this is Izakaya, thus the main reason to go is to talk. The taste is not bad, but if you want more strict Chinese cuisine, you'd better go to the restaurant. You see, I went to pay the ideas they used. A true chief should concentrate on the taste not on how to attract people from my point of view.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chichen Cooking]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/chichen-cooking/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/chichen-cooking/">
        </link>
        <updated>2023-07-30T12:38:17.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tried to cook chicken legs on the weekend.</p>
<p>The ingredients are very simple: spring onion, green peppers, potatoes, and chicken legs.</p>
<p>The method is also very simple: cut them all into pieces and stir-fry them, then add water and boil for about 15 mins. Add soy sauce and salt as you like.</p>
<p>I would like to say this dish is making large of the original flavor of the ingredients.<br>
<img src="https://yifeijing.github.io/post-images/1691754390844.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
<p>It also has good lookings.</p>
<p>The reason that I choose this is that it is always hard for only one person to cook all the ingredients all at one time. Because I only cook on the weekends so need to use up all the things bought from the market at one time. This choice satisfies all the requirements: tastes, quantity and looks. I cook only one time and I can have it for both lunch and dinner.</p>
<p>Would like to try more all-in-one dish in the future.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A summary in July]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/a-summary-in-july-dump/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/a-summary-in-july-dump/">
        </link>
        <updated>2023-07-12T13:51:11.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year has passed over a half. I think it is the time to make a mid point summary.</p>
<p>The biggest thing in this year should be I graduated and went to work in Rakuten. There was magnificent changes in March and April and it was also a very hard time, becasue I did not have friends in Tokyo.</p>
<p>The first thing I did was also to make some friends in the company. This is not hard. Because new grads want to extend relationships in the company. It is the strategy for the career, so all of them are very friendly. But you know it is not possible for people to get well on with all others, so the bond is just as it is looked. I would like to say it is better than nothing, because I got to hang out with some of them. Only several people will finally left to be callable friends, so they may support my daily life.</p>
<p>My progress on year's targets. I do not think I proceed with them well. Maybe I have made too big targets.</p>
<p>No stars on Github. I still do not have stars on github. This is reasonable, becasue I was not actually working on any self-made projects. Spending time reading other projects and tried to progress have been very time consuming. I did have finished reading many repositories. Mostly the musikcube.</p>
<p>Spent a lot of time playing apart from work. Made a new machine by myself. I made a new PC all by myself. The most expensive part is the RTX4070 card. Owing to that, I can play any games. I am playing OW2 now, it may be the only game I would like to play. Originally, I bought gears to play Euro Truck 2 and horizon 4, but I found no matter how struggled we tried on simulation, it is still impossible to compare to the real driving experience. When I ride my bike, I need to care for a lot of things on the road: the cars around me, the wind and temperature, the dirt on the road, the obstacles on the sides, etc. I have fatigue real for the riding not like just a number in the game. The feeling of accelaration is the most thing impossible to be simulated. So I gave up the driving games.</p>
<p>Tried on making girl friends and other friends to hang out. I have always wanted to make a girl friend, and I did try new ways in this year. Not only on the dating app, but also joined the parties. The results, I was not able to meet any girls from the dating app. I met some girls in the parties, but just got to talk is no progress. I got to make some salary men friends. One of them invited me to the matching party, which has a high participation fee and gaurantee that all members at the party are looking for partners. I then found that I cannot make any girl friend, because I just did not have the attraction to others. I am a boring person from many perspectives. This annoyed me very much, because I cannot solve this problem as this is my personality. But I still need to carry on, as I believe there must be someone who can accept me. As Dr. Luo has said what we can make in our life is so invisible that the life is surrounded by indefinity. So you may let the fortune decide for you or you have to. But you gotta get ready for that, because even the destiny has been defined by some power on you, you are the one to act the best on the time it comes.</p>
<p>I am feeling that the life is becoming bitter than ever though, I try to face it with every courage I can. All the effort on the life right now, to live, to die!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tokyo motor touring list]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/tokyo-motor-touring-list/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/tokyo-motor-touring-list/">
        </link>
        <updated>2023-05-13T08:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As it is known that the traffic in the street of tokyo is not suitable for motorcycles, this list amphasizes on the places with parking places for bikes.</p>
<ol>
<li>arima dam: no parking space though, you can park at the side of the road directly, as everyone do like this.</li>
<li>okutama: best place for riding in the mountain, have many parking space to rest.</li>
<li>城南島海浜公園: free parking space and places to sit</li>
<li>金田さざなみ公園: free parking space available</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2023年的奋斗目标]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/2023-nian-de-fen-dou-mu-biao/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/2023-nian-de-fen-dou-mu-biao/">
        </link>
        <updated>2023-01-12T08:55:26.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>GitHub拿到3个star</li>
<li>去2k+star仓库水一个PR</li>
<li>和大牛推友互动超过5句话</li>
<li>阅读和测试50个1k+star项目</li>
<li>坚持两个新习惯</li>
<li>谈一场恋爱</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[写在2022年11月]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/xie-zai-2022-nian-11-yue/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/xie-zai-2022-nian-11-yue/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-11-05T06:13:58.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>学校停电在家无事可做，回顾一下即将过去的一年吧。毕竟12月预计挺忙的。</p>
<p>这一年，放弃继续读博深造，决定了在日本就职并找到了一份互联网工作。<br>
这一年，开始了一项新爱好：二轮。从四月最初的Honda CBR250R到10月的大型二轮YAMAHA MT-09SP。由最初只是想试试新事物到逐渐着迷，深入研究引擎和机械结构，对器械工业有了一定理解。除此之外，试骑了KAWASAKI NINJA H2，HONDA CBR1000RR-R FIREBLADE这两辆顶级跑车。<br>
这一年，实现了经济独立，虽然还是学生，但通过便利店，学校，公司的打工获得了足够支撑个人生活开销，学杂费开销的收入。虽然一周工作超过30小时还要兼顾研究是很累的事，但感觉空下来就会胡思乱想，起码能充实的度过每一天也不差。<br>
这一年，认真的锻炼身体，虽然感觉体质还是和原来一样，不过肉眼可见的练出了形状，洗澡的时候总被大叔盯着看。。。（那句话咋说来着）<br>
这一年，终于贯通了从后端到前端的整个WEB开发流程。从零写了http服务器和几个基于React的UI。接触了Node.js。<br>
这一年，写出了基于OpenGL和Dear imgui的3D渲染系统。终于参透了OpenGL的流水线模型的设计思想。<br>
这一年，读完了APUE，没什么大的收获，开始肯Unix Socket。<br>
这一年，开始了对于DBMS的研究，在团队的帮助下接触了Oracle。开始了CMU的Bustub，希望从它的开发中加深理解。<br>
这一年，依然是孤身一人。和去年不同的是，没有交到新朋友，因为几乎所有的时间都在工作和研究。因为价值观和做事原则的问题和几个朋友决裂。从不解到愤怒到绝望到接受，用了将近半年时间。没有得到身边任何人的帮助，还是走过来了。我常常想假如最初显得合群一点，亲和一点，会不会也会有很多每天可以出去happy的朋友，也会找到可以交心的伴侣？</p>
<p>这一年下来是好是坏呢？也许还是在原地踏步。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When you need a warm hug]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/when-you-need-a-warm-hug/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/when-you-need-a-warm-hug/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-10-22T11:24:21.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That one person who maintains eye contact while everyone else is interrupting you. That one person you can communicate with just through a look. Feeling connected with another human being on that level is an amazing feeling. My mom would always bring sliced fruits to me when I live at home, and whenever I visit home she still does. You might think you will never feel the same feelings for someone else. You will, and that's going to be so much better. You are capable of loving and of being loved deeply over and over again.</p>
<p>Now let's take a deep breath until the screen turns black all of us together...</p>
<p>Hey, pick this word, <strong>that you are never going to settle for a life that you don't even like.</strong> Okay? So I created a Pinterest board for you of photos of things that I find to be comforting and calming and I hope you like it.</p>
<p>The fact that none of us expect to find cookies when we find an old cokie jar. <strong>Grief is just love with no place to go.</strong> Jamie Anderson wrote that. Did you know about it that has made it that squirrels accidentally plant millions of trees worldwide each year because they forget where they put their nuts and seeds. Squirrels are unintentionally saving forests and I don't think we give him credit. There is someone who when they think of their fondness memories you are in it, and you will never know. Your parents leaving the bedroom door cracked open when you were a kid to make you feel safe. The moment you realize that you have been sitting quietly with someone and it's been comfortable. It's rare but it's a beautiful thing when it happens. Wearing headphones when there is nothing playing. It makes me feel that I am wearing an invisibly cloak. It doesn't matter that it could have been or that others have it worse. Your feelings are valid. Don't let anyone tell you otherwise. The fact that saying, oh, Big Stretch! Every time our dog stretches is a universal thing. Laying in someone's arms as they play with your hair. Watching whatever you're baking expand in the oven... Trees covered in snow and a quiet forest. Pretty much everything that Carl Sagan has ever written like when he described what a book is writing: &quot;... one glance at it and you're inside and the mind of another person, maybe somebody dead for thousands of years. Across the millennia, an author is speaking clearly and silently inside your head, directly to you. Writing is perhaps the greatest of human inventions, binding together people who never knew each other, citizens of distant epochs.&quot;</p>
<p>Morning stuffs. Morning cuddles, morning coffee, morning texts, morning walks,... On times when I've laid awake at night, unable to sleep. Perhaps feeling uneasy, I have found comfort in knowing that somewhere in the world, it's morning or daytime. Someone is getting ready for their day. Another is have lunch. The sun is always shining somewhere. Just keep swimming, just keep swimming. I first saw Nemo when I was 9 or 10 and to this day I find myself repeating those words of Dory whenever I need them. <strong>Nothing happens to anyman which is not formed by nature to Bear.</strong> Marcus Aurelius wrote that. The street light coming on when it get dark outside. Libraries, Ikea, Bob Ross making tea in a kettle on a gas just seeing humans. Human like seeing someone accidentally tripping over something on the street or failing over wouldn't sleep away outside. Someone trying to suit their crying baby. Someone carrying too many grocery bags or spilling something on themselves. It's all, just, authentic. The word 'mellifluous', which means a sound that is pleasingly smooth and musical to hear. <strong>You didn't deserve what was done to you and I'm sorry you have to go through that.</strong> Forehead kisses, trust me on this one, not everything needs be to questioned some. Something will never be understood. Let it be, sometimes it's the only way of setting yourself free.</p>
<p>There's something comforting about knowing that when it rains, everyone in the city or whatever you live notices and everyone who was outside gets wet. <strong>Rain is never personal.</strong> &quot;tu me manques&quot;: French for &quot;I miss you&quot; --- literal translating is you are missing from me. I think that's beautiful. Your dog is always excited to see you. You are their whole world. It might get worse before it gets better. But it does get better. This is not as goog as it gets. It's Okay to just lay in bed when you're having a difficult day. You don't need to try and turn it around. Just know that tomorrow is a new day and you will never have to do this day again. Everything will be okay.</p>
<p>Lana Blakely</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MT-09SP 2022 纳车！]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/mt-09sp-2022-na-che/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/mt-09sp-2022-na-che/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-10-08T09:38:12.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>从预定到纳车没想到就等了一个月。<br>
这次是全新的888cc YAMAHA MT-09sp！直列三缸引擎CP3，搭载九轴陀螺仪，TCS，Quickshifter和巡航系统。大概是目前性价比最高的大型二轮了。哦哦哦哦哦哦哦哦哦！<br>
新车要慣らし運転1000km。这1000km不能跑超5000rpm，以及要用输出最低的Mode 4。简单的讲就是磨合期。不仅是引擎，轮胎和刹车也要磨合。因为新胎比较硬，所以更容易打滑。。。刹车片也是新的，非常滑，刚开始刹车就非常不好用。不过因为本身就全都是新的，刚开始走行就会闻到各种焦味，耐热胶啊，排气管啊，引擎上的部件之类的。接下来的一个月要各处旅行了！<img src="https://yifeijing.github.io/post-images/1671094298388.JPG" alt="" loading="lazy"></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to integrate imgui to OpenGL application rendering pipeline]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/how-to-integrate-imgui-to-opengl-application-rendering-pipeline/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/how-to-integrate-imgui-to-opengl-application-rendering-pipeline/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-06-16T10:34:18.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The idea of <em>Dear imgui</em> :</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It outputs optimized vertex buffers that you can render anytime in your 3D-pipeline enabled application</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Which has meaned that adding these optmized vertex buffers at any time in the rendering pipeline is possible.</p>
<p>Also the CMakeFileLists of standalone imgui library is used to integrate this UI to any program!</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[第一辆车决定是你了CBR250R]]></title>
        <id>https://yifeijing.github.io/post/di-yi-liang-che-jue-ding-shi-ni-liao-cbr250r/</id>
        <link href="https://yifeijing.github.io/post/di-yi-liang-che-jue-ding-shi-ni-liao-cbr250r/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-04-11T10:27:29.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>看了三周，Goobike，twitter和福冈本地的车店。最后还是决定Goobike了。250cc的中古车价格都挺离谱的，明明都已经骑了很久的车，依然能卖到全新的80%左右。姑且挑了一辆最便宜的CBR250R 2011黑色款。车子22万，不过加了服务费和运费（要从神户运过来）就是30万了。运费4万多真是离谱，而且还是要等一个月（5/13）才能送过来，没想到货运这么缺人，没想到货运这么赚钱。不过买下了，真的期待。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>